Claire Falkenstein
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Commissions, 1930-1992, Series 5:; (Box 21-22, OV 50-54; 2 linear feet)
  - California State University, Dominquez Hills - "The Forum," 1980, (8 folders, oversized item housed in Box 42) (Box 21, Folder 29-36)
  - California State University, Dominquez Hills - "The Forum" Dedication, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - California State College, Fullerton, Men's Gymnasium - "Game Relief," 1964-1965, (2 folders, oversized item housed in OV 53) (Box 21, Folder 38-39)
  - California State University, Long Beach - First International Sculpture Symposium, 1965, 1969, (oversized item housed in OV 53) (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - California State University, Long Beach - First International Sculpture Symposium - "Expanding Air Structure," 1965, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - California State University, Northridge - "American in Paris: The 1950s," 1979 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - California State University, Stanislow, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - City Hall, Los Angeles - "The Surf, Skeleton of a Wave," 1983 (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - Commission Applications, 1990-1992 (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - Coos Bay, Oregon - "Sign of the Pacific," 1973-1976 (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - City of Coos Bay, Oregon - "Sign of the Pacific" Vandalism Damage, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 47)
  - Datamation Magazine Cover, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - Diana Ross Home - Stained Glass Window, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 49)
  - Peggie Dwight Ring, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 50)
  - Fresno Mall - "Three Fires," 1964-1966, 1973, (2 folders) (Box 21, Folder 51-52)
  - Golden Gateway North, San Francisco - "Tide Pool Fountain," 1982-1983, (oversized item housed in OV 53) (Box 21, Folder 53)
  - Ray Green - Album Cover, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 54)
  - Peggy Guggenheim Gates, 1961-1964 (Box 21, Folder 55)
  - The Head-Royce School - Alumni/Student Art Show, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 56)
  - Louis Heyn - "Structure and Flow #3," 1969 (Box 21, Folder 57)
  - Louis Heyn - "Structure and Flow #3" Donated to Long Beach Museum of Art, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 58)
  - Hyland Lab, Costa Mesa - "DNA Molecule," 1969-1970, (Oversized item housed in OV 53) (Box 21, Folder 59-60)
  - Joseph Magnin, Inc., 1965, (oversized item housed in OV 54) (Box 21, Folder 61)
  - Alan Leslie - "Never Ending Screen" and "Coachella Valley," 1984 (Box 21, Folder 62)
  - Arthur and Edith Levin - Suspended Pieces, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 63)
  - Arthur J. Levin - "Space Variables," 1978 (Box 21, Folder 64)
  - Lewis and Clark Mural Proposal, circa 1945 (Box 21, Folder 65)
  - Liethold Residence, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 66)
  - Long Beach Museum of Art - Heyn Fountain Gift, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Los Angeles Harbor Department, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Maryland National Capital Park and Planning Commission, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Mayer Family, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Murals, 1943-1944 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Mural at U.S. Naval Hospital, San Leandro, CA, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Research on Murals, circa 1940-1945 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Don and Helen Olsen Mural, 1955-1956, (oversized item housed in OV 51) (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Painted Costume for Ray Green and May O'Donnell Show, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - James Pick - "Never Ending Screen," 1980-1981 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Public Arts Program, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Jack Quinn - "Gates," 1992 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Rich's Department Store, Knoxville, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Sam Rubenstein Windows, 1971-1972, (oversized item housed in OV 51) (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - St. Basil's Church, circa 1964-1966 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - St. Basil's Church, circa 1967-1969, (3 folders, oversized item housed in OV 52) (Box 22, Folder 16-18)
  - St. Basil's Church - Publicity, 1968-1975 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - St. Basil's Church - Model for Windows, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - St. Basil's Church - Contract Correspondence, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - St. Basil's Church - Contracts, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - St. Basil's Church - Finances, 1967-1969, (Oversized items housed in OV 52) (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - St. Luke's Church, Long Beach - "Sun Dial," 1969-1970 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - San Diego State University, Library Classroom Building, 1970, (oversized item in OV 50) (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Henry Segerstrom - Two Copper and Venetian Glass Gates, 1987-1988, (oversized item in OV 51) (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - South Coast Plaza, Costa Mesa - Gates, 1982, (2 folders) (Box 22, Folder 27-28)
  - Louis Stratham, Lone Pine, California - Sculpture, 1973-1974, (Oversized items housed in OV 53) (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - William Street - Fireplace Screen, 1981-1982 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Submissions for Commission Projects, 1982-1983 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - U.S. Naval Hospital, San Leandro, CA, 1944-1945 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - University of California, Los Angeles - "Point as Set #25," 1970-1971 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - University of Southern California, Eileen Norris Cinema Building - "Film Strip," 1975-1976 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Leopold Vitorage, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Oversized California State University - Dominquez Hills - "The Forum," 1986, (from Box 21, F. 29) (Box 42)
  - Oversized Architectural Plans for Unidentified House, circa 1965-1975 (Box 42)
  - Oversized San Diego State University, Library Classroom Building, 1970, (from Box 22, F. 25) (Box OV 50)
  - Oversized Knoxville, Tennessee Department Store - Rough Preliminary Drawing, 1955 (Box OV 50)
  - Oversized Galerie Stadler, Paris - Drawings for Staircase Sculpture, 1955 (Box OV 51)
  - Oversized Donald Olsen - Drawing of Mural in Stairwell, 1956, (from Box 22, F. 8) (Box OV 51)
  - Oversized Sam Rubenstein - Drawing for Windows, 1971-1972, (from Box 22, F. 14) (Box OV 51)
  - Oversized Henry Segerstrom - Drawings for Two Copper and Venetian Glass Gates,1987, (from Box 22, F. 26) (Box OV 51)
  - Oversized St. Basil's Church - Monthly Expense Sheets, 1967-1969, (15 sheets); (from Box 22, F. 23) (Box OV 52)
  - Oversized St. Basil's Church - Progress Schedule, 1967-1969, (2 sheets, from Box 22, F. 16-18) (Box OV 52)
  - Oversized St. Basil's Church - Drawing for Narthex, circa 1967, (from Box 22, F. 16-18) (Box OV 52)
  - Oversized St. Basil's Church - Drawings for Bronze Doors, 1967, (3 sheets); (from Box 22, F. 16-18) (Box OV 52)
  - Oversized St. Basil's Church - Details for Narthex, Nave, and Tower Windows, 1967-1969, (from Box 22, F. 16-18)) (Box OV 52)
  - Oversized California State University, Long Beach - First International Sculpture Symposium - Supports for Sculpture, 1965, (from Box 21, F. 40) (Box OV 53)
  - Oversized Louis Stratham, Lone Pine, California - Drawing for "Fire and Ice" Lamps on Fence and "Structure and Flow #4" Fountain, 1973-1974, (from Box 22, F. 29) (Box OV 53)
  - Oversized California State College, Fullerton, Men's Gymnasium - Plan for Relief called "Game Wall," 1965, (from Box 21, F. 38-39) (Box OV 53)
  - Oversized Golden Gateway North, San Francisco - Plan for "Tide Pool Fountain," 1981-1982, (from Box 21, F. 53) (Box OV 53)
  - Oversized Hyland Laboratories, Costa Mesa - Plans and Drawings for "DNA Molecules," 1970, (5 sheets, from Box 21, F. 59-60) (Box OV 53)
  - Oversized Sam Rubenstein - "Tide Pools," 1981, (2 drawings) (Box OV 53)
  - Oversized Joseph Magnin, Inc. - Plans for Sculpture, 1965, (2 sheets, from Box 21, F. 61) (Box OV 54)
  - Oversized Ambassador College, Pasadena - General Landscape Grading Plan, 1957 (Box OV 54)
- Writings, circa 1929-1993, Series 6:; (Box 22-26, 42, 55; 4.6 linear feet)
  Falkenstein's work as a prolific writer, particularly in the 1940s and 1950s, is well-documented here through her numerous published articles in Arts and Architecture magazine, and the New York Herald-Tribune. Her work for Arts and Architecture was primarily written for the "Art Comments from San Francisco" section. She was living in Paris when she contributed an art news column to the New York Herald-Tribune.
  Also found here are five diaries and one journal dating from circa 1929-1978. The entries are inconsistent and concern mostly travel. The diaries from 1929 and 1934 are more personal. Falkenstein also maintained extensive notes and notebooks about artwork ideas, observations about art, research, and even drafts of letters. There are also many notes about various topics, including art and class notes. Additional writings are eclectic and cover a wide range of topics of interest to Falkenstein, including music, poetry, the script for Falkestein's film entitled Touching the Quick and drafts of her unpublished book on murals. A handful of writings by others are found, most with annotations by Falkenstein.
  Writings are arranged into 5 subseries:
  6.1: Published Articles, 1948-1958
  6.2: Diaries and Journals, 1929-1978
  6.3: Notes and Notebooks, circa 1930-1989
  6.4: Other Writings By Falkenstein, circa 1929-1993
  6.5: Writings By Others, circa 1938-1972
  - Published Articles, 1948-1958, 6.1:
    This subseries contains published articles, the majority of which were written for the "Art Comments from San Francisco" section of Arts and Architecture magazine. The files contain drafts and notes for the articles, copies of the published material, and correspondence with editors. When Falkenstein moved to Paris in the early 1950s, she supplemented her income by writing a column on art news for the New York Herald Tribune. These articles are also found here.
    Files are arranged alphabetically by publication and then chronologically by date. File contents are arranged chronologically.
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, February 1948, April 1948 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, April 1948 (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, June-July, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Article in Arts and Architecture - "Art in Cinema," October 1948 (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, November-December 1948 (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, Review of "Masterpieces from Berlin Masters" Exhibit, circa 1948 (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, circa 1947-1950 (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, 1948-1949 (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, circa 1948-1949 (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, March 1949, May 1949 (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, August-September 1949 (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, November 1949 (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, circa 1949-19501950 (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, March 1950, May 1950 (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - Articles in Arts and Architecture, circa 1952-1958 (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - Article - New York Herald-Tribune, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 51)
    - Article - San Francisco Chronicle, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 52)
    - Drafts of Published Articles, circa 1948-1958 (Box 22, Folder 53)
    - Drafts of Published Articles, circa 1951-1958 (Box 22, Folder 54)
  - Diaries and Journals, 1929-1978, 6.2:
    Diaries are not complete and are limited. Most of the volumes focus on travel, with observations about art and architecture, visits with friends, and her efforts to work on her art while traveling. The diaries from 1929 and 1934 contain more personal entries about love and relationships.
    - Diary, circa 1929 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Diary with Poems, 1934 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Diaries, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Diary, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Diary of Trip to Europe, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Journal, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Notes and Notebooks, circa 1930-1989, 6.3:
    Throughout her life, Falkenstein maintained files containing notes about events in her life, including ideas and plans for her artwork; observations about meetings, exhibitions, commissions, and lectures; lists of art supply purchases; research notes; and reminders about upcoming activites. Some files contain drafts of letters.
    - Notes, circa 1930-1990, (13 folders) (Box 23, Folder 7-19)
    - Notebooks, circa 1940-1960, (12 folders) (Box 23, Folder 20-31)
    - Notebooks, circa 1966-1985, (22 folders) (Box 24, Folder 1-22)
    - Notebooks, circa 1985-1989, (4 folders) (Box 25, Folder 1-4)
  - Other Writings by Falkenstein, circa 1929-1993, 6.4:
    Eclectic writings by Falkenstein are mostly unpublished, beginning with her writings as an undergraduate at UC, Berkeley and ending with her observations about her artwork in the 1990s. Travel notes are not diary entries but more formal writings about tours Falkenstein organized in France and Italy. Of particular interest are the poetry and music files which document Falkenstein's wide range of artistic endeavors. This subseries also contains notes and the script for Falkestein's film entitled Touching the Quick and drafts of her unpublished book on murals. The observations on her artwork contain notes and more formal writings on specific pieces of sculpture.
    The files are arranged by type of material. File contents are arranged chronologically.
    - Class Notes - UC Berkeley, circa 1929, (7 folders) (Box 25, Folder 5-11)
    - Notes from Anatomy Class, circa 1930, (2 folders) (Box 25, Folder 12-13)
    - Notes on Trip to Mexico, 1934 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Notes from Drive Across Country, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Notes on trip to Italy and France, circa 1959-1960 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Notes from Trip to Italy, circa 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Notes from Trip to Paris, circa 1993 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Poetry, 1932-1954, (3 folders, oversized item housed in OV 55) (Box 25, Folder 19-21)
    - Notes, including Poetry, circa 1932-1938, (2 folders) (Box 25, Folder 22-23)
    - Music, circa 1933, (6 folders) (Box 25, Folder 24-29)
    - Notes on Falkenstein's Film "Touching the Quick," circa 1948 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Script and Direction for Falkenstein's Film "Touching the Quick," circa 1948 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Drafts of Book on Murals, circa 1950, (4 folders) (Box 25, Folder 32-35)
    - Notes on Book on Murals, circa 1950 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Notes on Artwork "The Sun" Series, circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Notes on Artwork "Sculptured Water," 1963-1965 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Notes on Artwork "Vibration," 1965 (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Notes on Artwork "Structure and Flow," circa 1965-1969 (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - Notes on Artwork "Simultaneity," circa 1970 (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Notes on Artwork "Fertility," Undated (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - Notes on Vocabulary for Artwork "Exploding the Volume," circa 1980-1990 (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Notes on Sculpture, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Notes on Works of Art, circa 1947-1984 (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - Notes on Art Techniques and Supplies, circa 1945 (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - Learning French, circa 1951 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Museum Report for School Project, circa 1928 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Notes on Discussion with Frank Lobdell and Tom Roberts, 1951 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Notes from The Anatomy of Art by Herbert Read, circa 1935-1940 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Writings on Aesthetics, circa 1960 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Oversized Text from Falkenstein's Film "Seven Episodes, Seven Works," circa 1976 (Box 42)
    - Oversized Poetry, 1933, (from Box 24, F. 8-10) (Box OV 55)
  - Writings by Others, circa 1938-1972, 6.5:
    This subseries contains writings by other authors, most of which contain annotations by Falkenstein. Of particular interest is a signed handwritten document in French by Francis Picabia.
    The files are arranged chronologically by date.
    - Bernard Zakheim, circa 1938 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Amedee Ozenfant, 1942 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Francis Picabia, 1950 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Peter Jones, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 9)
- Teaching, 1929-1995, Series 7:; (Box 26; .8 linear feet)
  This series documents Falkenstein's long career as a teacher and lecturer with correspondence, contracts, and notes on her many lecture engagements at schools, galleries, museums, and art associations. The remaining files document Falkenstein's teaching positions, including her first position at Mills College in California from 1946-1947. These files include lesson plans and notes, contracts, and correspondence. The files on her tenure at the Pond Farm Workshops are particularly interesting, with notes about her fellow teacher Frans Wildenhain and correspondence with workshop owners, Jane and Gordon Herr.
  - California Labor School, 1945-1947, (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 10-11)
  - California School of Fine Arts, 1946-1950, 1958, (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 12-13)
  - California State University, Distinguished Artists' Forum, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Claremont Graduate School, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - College Art Association, 1980-1981 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - East Bay Teachers' Union Program for Elementary and Secondary Schools, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Lectures, circa 1945-1995, (5 folders) (Box 26, Folder 18-22)
  - Long Beach Museum of Art - Lecture Notes, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Los Angeles County Schools - Galleries-in-the-Schools Workshop, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Los Angeles District Assembly of Delphian Chapters, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Mills College, circa 1945-1947, (5 folders) (Box 26, Folder 26-30)
  - Patri School of Art Fundamentals,1948 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - The Pilchuk School, Seattle, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Pond Farm Workshops, Guerneville, California, 1949-1950, (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 33-34)
  - San Francisco Museum of Art, circa 1945-1949, (3 folders) (Box 26, Folder 35-37)
  - San Jose Art League, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - Teaching Notes, 1939-1950, (8 folders) (Box 26, Folder 39-46)
  - University of California, Davis, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 47)
  - University of California, Riverside, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 48)
  - University of Southern California, Friends of Fine Arts Studio Tour and Lecture, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 49)
  - University of Southern California, Idyllwild Campus, circa 1982-1985, (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 50-51)
  - UCLA Extension Course, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 52)
  - UCLA Faculty Women's Club, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 53)
  - Utah State University, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 54)
  - Writings on Teaching, circa 1946-1947 (Box 26, Folder 55)
- Photographs, circa 1890-1997, Series 8:; (Box 27-35, 43, 55-56; 9.5 linear feet)
  There are extensive photographs of Falkenstein, her family and friends, colleagues, commissions, exhibitions, and works of art. These images provide an exhaustive visual inventory of her art from her first wood sculptures to her last commission at California State University, Dominiquez Hills in 1986. Included are many images of Falkenstein, of Falkenstien with her art, of Falkentstien working, and of Falkenstein's studio. There are numerous photographs of Falkenstein with friends, family, and colleagues in social or work settings. Also found are photographs of exhibition openings, installation views, and works of art exhibited. Additional photographs document Falkenstein's commissions, including images of her at work. Other images of commissions may also be found in the Commissions series, but the bulk are filed here. There are numerous photographs of Falkenstein's individual works of art, including drawings, sculpture, jewelry, murals, lamps, and ceramics.
  Photographs are arranged into 8 subseries:
  8.1: Falkenstein, circa 1920-1997
  8.2: Falkenstein with Family and Friends, 1933-1997
  8.3: Family and Friends,circa 1890-1997
  8.4: Travel, 1935-1978
  8.5. Commissions, 1944-1995
  8.6: Exhibitions, 1941-1995
  8.7: Works of Art, circa 1935-1995
  8.8: Miscellaneous, 1933-1995
  - Falkenstein, 1974-1991, 8.1:
    Photographs of Falkenstein are arranged into 3 subsubseries:
    8.1.1: Single Images, circa 1920-1997
    8.1.2: Working, circa 1946-1997
    8.1.3: Studio and House, 1965-1997
    - Single Images, circa 1920-1997, 8.1.1:
      These files contain single images of Falkenstein, including several photographs taken a few months before her death in 1997. The self-portraits are photographs of drawings Falkenstein made of herself using an old photograph as a guide.
      - Claire Falkenstein, circa 1920-1950, (2 folders) (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
      - Claire Falkenstein, circa 1951-1997, (3 folders, oversized items housed in OV 56) (Box 27, Folder 3-5)
      - Self-Portraits, circa 1930 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - Claire Falkenstein in her Garden, circa 1978-1980 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Claire Falkenstein on Horseback, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Claire Falkenstein Negatives, circa 1920-1950 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Claire Falkenstein Negatives, circa 1950-1997 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Working, circa 1946-1997, 8.1.2:
      These files contain photographs of Falkenstein with her works of art, both posed shots with artwork as well as more informal shots of her working in her California and Paris studios.
      - Claire Falkenstein with her Works of Art, circa 1946-1997, (5 folders, oversized items housed in Box 43) (Box 27, Folder 11-15)
      - Claire Falkenstein with Her Works of Art in Paris, circa 1953-1955 (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - Claire Falkenstein with "Spring Stampede," circa 1988 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Claire Falkenstein Working on her Art, circa 1946-1996, (3 folders) (Box 27, Folder 18-20)
      - Claire Falkenstein Working in her Studio, circa 1990-1992 (Box 27, Folder 21)
      - Claire Falkenstein with her Works of Art - Negatives, circa 1946-1997 (Box 27, Folder 22)
      - Claire Falkenstein with her Works of Art - Negatives, circa 1946-1997 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Studios and House, 1965-1997, 8.1.3:
      Throughout much of her career, Falkenstein maintained studios in California and Paris. These files capture both spaces. In the early 1960s, Falkenstein purchased waterfront property in Venice, California and created living quarters with an attached studio large enough to work on her sculptures. She renovated the space again in the late 1980s. Photographs here capture this space.
      - Ocean Front Walk Studio and House Construction, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 24)
      - Ocean Front Walk Property Studio and Garden, circa 1965 (Box 27, Folder 25)
      - Ocean Front Walk Studio, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 26)
      - Paris Studio, circa 1975-1985 (Box 27, Folder 27)
      - Ocean Front Walk Property Garden, circa 1980 (Box 27, Folder 28)
      - Ocean Front Walk Property Upstairs Studio, circa 1990 (Box 27, Folder 29)
      - Ocean Front Walk Property, circa 1990 (Box 27, Folder 30)
      - Ocean Front Walk Studio - Renovation, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 31)
      - Ocean Front Walk Property House and Studio, circa 1990-1997 (Box 27, Folder 32)
      - Beach Scenes from Ocean Front Walk Property, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 33)
      - Ocean Front Walk Property Studio - Negatives, circa 1965-1990 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Falkenstein with Family and Friends, 1933-1997, 8.2:
    This subseries contains images of Falkestein with her family, friends, and colleagues. They include both identified and unidentified individuals posing with Falkenstein. Many images are group shots taken at dinners, parties, or outings. Of particular interest are the images of Falkenstein with her friend, Michel Tapie. The files also contain early images of Falkenstein with her husband, Richard McCarthy
    The photographs with identified individual(s) are marked and filed at the beginning of the subseries. Unidentified individuals with Falkenstein are in the general files at the end of the subseries.
    - Claire Falkenstein with Helen Bickel (sister), circa 1933, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - Claire Falkenstein with Betty Freeman - Dinner Party, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - Claire Falkenstein with Diane Divelbess, circa 1980-1982 (Box 27, Folder 37)